□707-299-9216 | ☑ daranzolin@gmail.com | 🎢 daranzolin.github.io | ⊙ daranzolin | 🛅 dranzolin

#### Overview

Skilled analyst, programmer, and GIS specialist who can get, clean, analyze, and communicate data.

#### LANGUAGES AND APPLICATIONS

 R, SQL, D3.js, HTML/CSS, Bash (UNIX shell), GitHub, RStudio, ArcMap/ArcGIS Pro, SQL Server, Excel/Google Sheets, IBM Cognos Analytics, Confluence

#### **TECHNIQUES**

• Data visualization, statistics, spatial analysis, web scraping, APIs, package development

#### SOFTWARE

- ViewPipeSteps Generate View() tabs for each %>%.
- d3rain 'Raindrop' visualizations in R with d3.js.
- pinpoint Explore small distributions with d3.js.
- rcanvas R client for the Canvas LMS API.

## **Experience**

#### San Francisco State University

San Francisco, CA

SENIOR INSTITUTIONAL RESEARCH ANALYST

Apr 2019 - Present

• R developer and creator of 'rsfsu', our department's internal R package. Within the package are plot and table themes, connections to various databases and APIs, report, slide, and project templates, calculations, and other miscellaneous functions. Architect for minor ETL projects. Collaborated with stakeholders on a variety of institutional research analyses.

#### **UCSC Extension Silicon Valley**

Santa Clara, CA

DATA ANALYST

Jan 2017 - Mar 2019

• Gathered, cleaned, assembled, and visualized data; performed analytical studies on a variety of policies, programs and issues; and participated in administrative policy and program planning and development. Assisted the Senior Business Analyst with ETL solutions. Cognos Analytics report author and trainer. Data Governance Group Chair. Knowledge base administrator (Confluence).

### **Scout from University of California**

Santa Clara, CA

DATA ANALYST

Feb 2014 - Dec 2016

• Networked with K-12 educators and conducted a variety of analyses requiring knowledge of: (1) University administrative organization, policies, procedures, and practices; (2) K-12 online education; (3) instructional design; and (4) statistical methods. Staff Advisory Board member.

## **Education**

**Emory University**Atlanta, GA

MASTER OF THEOLOGICAL STUDIES

2011 - 2013

• Area of Focus: History and Tradition

Pacific Union College
BA IN RELIGIOUS STUDIES/BA IN ENGLISH

Angwin, CA

2005 - 2009

• Emphases: History, Writing

UCSC Extension Silicon Valley

Santa Clara, CA

CERTIFICATE IN DATABASE AND DATA ANALYTICS

• Coursework in R, SQL, Python, databases, and machine learning.

2014 - 2016

# Awards

#### Staff Appreciation and Recognition Award (2x)

SCOUT FROM UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA

2015, 2016

In recognition of exemplary performance and contributions which further operational and administrative improvements within the university.
 Myki Mobley Award

EMORY UNIVERSITY 2013

· For outstanding academic performance.